<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>itp blog</title>
 <link href="ratemypraxis.github.io/itp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="ratemypraxis.github.io/itp/"/>
 <updated>2023-01-26T20:20:57+00:00</updated>
 <id>ratemypraxis.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>sim</name>
   <email>sh4712@nyu.edu</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Making a small box</title>
   <link href="ratemypraxis.github.io/itp/2023/01/26/small-box"/>
   <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>ratemypraxis.github.io/2023/01/26/small-box</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;How I made my first little box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I went ahead and selected a piece of wood to start from. I went with this long piece from the scrap bin, it might even be the same piece used in class for the demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ratemypraxis/itp/master/_posts/preBoxWood.png&quot; alt=&quot;rectangular piece of wood held by an arm wearing a colorful striped sweater.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, after turning on the dust collecter thing, I went ahead and sanded all sides of the piece on one end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I measures the piece out and marked where I could cut it to make a perfect square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I cut it with the circular saw before taking it to the drill press where this occured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ratemypraxis/itp/master/_posts/issuewk1fab.png&quot; alt=&quot;A small square piece of wood stuck in a drill bit attached to a drill press.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stop the drill press immediatley and just moved on because I though it had gone in enough. After cutting a bit of bit of wood off of the side off to make a lid using the belt saw I realized that the drill bit had not gone in deep enough to extent beyond where I cut the lid. So I decided to start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I repeated everything above again (except the measuring and cutting to square moment). When I got to the drill press I was able to get a bit more progress, I think because I had adjusted the height and moved a little quicker but because their was no clamp the piece of wood stuck to the drill bit and spun around, I again stopped the drill press and just moved on to the belt saw where I cut the lid just right to have a hold from the press present on both pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the press to make use of one of those big bits from the drawer. Immediatley it was clear that without a clamp I was gonna get nowhere so I consulted the shop staff on duty who suggessted using the big bit in a hand drill with the table clamp. While this process took a bit more force and time it seemed to have a similar effect (although the hole is a little oval-like). I then tried inserting a screw with the hand dril but as always it got crooked so I undid it with a screwdriver and was able to put it in more straight using that tool. Lastly, I went a little silly and started to color over accent lines with a purple sharpie but the ink spread within the wood grains which I am not very happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ratemypraxis/itp/master/_posts/box1closed.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a small wooden box with a screw on top and a division one eigth of the way down form the top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ratemypraxis/itp/master/_posts/box1open.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a small wooden box with a lid slightly ajar revealing an embedded circular hole.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to leave town last minute to deal with a family situation but if I have time when I return I want to try decorating it with other materials and try to make another box using this piece of wood I cut from a bigger cylinder piece in the scrap bin.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What is the Live Web?</title>
   <link href="ratemypraxis.github.io/itp/2023/01/25/what-is-the-live-web"/>
   <updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>ratemypraxis.github.io/2023/01/25/what-is-the-live-web</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is the Live Web?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework: Write a blog post detailing the last “live” media you consumed. Answer these questions: What was it? Why did you consume it “live” or in real time? How was your relationship to the media or others affected through the “live” consumption of it? What was missing in your experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assignment: use html, javascript, css with media elements to make a self-portrait in any sense of the term. think about multiple media, interaction, time based interaction in the context of a webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Redesigning Interaction</title>
   <link href="ratemypraxis.github.io/itp/2023/01/25/redesigning-interaction"/>
   <updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>ratemypraxis.github.io/2023/01/25/redesigning-interaction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Due Week 2 (Blog post by 7pm on Monday, January 31)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Observation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend some time in the bathrooms at 370 Jay to observe intangible interactions (automatic toilet flush system, faucet, towel dispenser…). I encourage you to analyze the interaction using Implicit Interaction Framework. If you want to read more about the framework, see Chapter 2 of The Design of Implicit Interactions (pw: intangible).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if you find a non-intangible interaction that you want to replace with intangible interaction, you can observe and research them instead.
example of implicit interaction design frameworkAn example of an analysis using implicit interaction design framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 Research&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the sensing system works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1) Take a closer look at the system for some time and play with it by trying different actions. What did you find out? What is the most common error of the system?
2) Search relevant information online. Consider these questions: Which sensors are being use in the current systems using? How are they programmed? How are they embedded on the device? How do they decide when to activate (flushing, dispensing, making sound…)? 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 Ideation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more time after observation and research, identify what the most common errors are in the system, and answer either of these questions. Feel free to make a simple sketch of your ideas. * Note that this is about ideation only and you’re not expected to make anything for this. The examples by previous students below show prototypes since the instruction was different at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Option 1. If you were to redesign it, how would you improve the system?
    As an example, does the system give enough feedback for the intangible interaction? Would adding feedback indicator that shows the status of the system or interaction feedback be helpful? (e.g., LED indicator, alarm sound, voice…).
    Michelle and Schuyler’s toilet doors can be another example.
Option 2. Can you think of creative ways of taking advantage of the erroneous system? It can be a whimsical interaction that is totally useless.
    In case you’re curious, some examples from past years’ students are (with a focus on toilet): Lu Lyu’s Kissing Frog, Name and Themis’ Gamble Flusher, Rae and Yiting’s Pooping Toilet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
